[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a subfield of neuroscience?",
        "A1": "Neurology",
        "A2": "Neuropharmacology",
        "A3": "Computational Neuroscience",
        "A4": "Nephrology",
        "correct-answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the part of a neuron which primarily recieves signals?",
        "A1": "Axon",
        "A2": "Dendrite",
        "A3": "Myelin",
        "A4": "Cell Body",
        "correct-answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "A sensory neuron location in the hand would be considered a...",
        "A1": "Peripheral afferent neuron",
        "A2": "Peripheral efferent neuron",
        "A3": "Central afferent neuron",
        "A4": "Central efferent neuron",
        "correct-answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What cell in the brain is capable of phagocytoisis as part of an immune function?",
        "A1": "Schwann Cells",
        "A2": "Oligidendrocyes",
        "A3": "Microgalia",
        "A4": "Macrogalia",
        "correct-answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "All of these are function of glia cells EXCEPT...",
        "A1": "Synthesising neurotransmitters",
        "A2": "Maintaining a proper ionic milieu",
        "A3": "Promotion neuron survival",
        "A4": "Synthesising myelin",
        "correct-answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Control of the body's voluntary muscles is orchestrated by the...",
        "A1": "Sympathetic nervous system",
        "A2": "parasympathetic nervous system",
        "A3": "autonomic nervous system",
        "A4": "somatic nervous system",
        "correct-answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Rapid heart-rate, sweating, dilated pupils and faster breating indicate actvation of which nervous system branch?",
        "A1": "sympathetic nervous system",
        "A2": "parasympathetic nervous system",
        "A3": "peripheral nervous system",
        "A4": "somatic nervous system",
        "correct-answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Select all of the following which are closely related to the action of the neurotransmitter 'dopamine'",
        "A1": "Reward circuits",
        "A2": "Sleep",
        "A3": "Memory",
        "A4": "Impulse Control",
        "A5": "Inhibition",
        "correct-answer": 1 & 4
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary inhibitory neurotransitter of the central nervous system?",
        "A1": "Glutamine",
        "A2": "GABA",
        "A3": "Acetylcholine",
        "A4": "Seratonin",
        "correct-answer": 2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Opening a potassium ion (K+) channel would have what effect on the neuron's membrane potential?",
        "A1": "Depolarisation",
        "A2": "Hyperpolarisation",
        "A3": "Firing of an action potential",
        "A4": "Destruction",
        "correct-answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Opening a potassium ion (K+) channel would have what effect on the neuron's membrane potential?",
        "A1": "Depolarisation",
        "A2": "Hyperpolarisation",
        "A3": "Firing of an action potential",
        "A4": "Destruction",
        "correct-answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Opening a potassium ion (K+) channel would have what effect on the neuron's membrane potential?",
        "A1": "Depolarisation",
        "A2": "Hyperpolarisation",
        "A3": "Firing of an action potential",
        "A4": "Destruction",
        "correct-answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the 'all or none' principle of synaptic transmission?",
        "A1": "When neurotransmitters are released, it will either open all sodium channels or none dependant on how much is released",
        "A2": "If the membrane potential exceeds a certain threshold, the sell will send a single signal",
        "A3": "If the excitation is strong enough, then a hyperpolarisation phase will occur",
        "A4": "None of the above",
        "correct-answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following brain structures exist as pairs in the human brain",
        "A1": "Hippocampus",
        "A2": "Temporal lobe",
        "A3": "Hypothalamus",
        "A4": "Thalamus",
        "A5": "Amygdala",
        "correct-answer": 1 , 2 , 4 , 5
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following are considered part of the brain stem EXCEPT...",
        "A1": "Cerebellum",
        "A2": "Midbrain",
        "A3": "Pons",
        "A4": "Medulla",
        "correct-answer": 1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the following which are functions of the hypothalamus",
        "A1": "Feeding",
        "A2": "Fighting",
        "A3": "Fleeing",
        "A4": "Fornicating",
        "correct-answer": 1, 2, 3, 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the following brain regions that are correctly matched to their function",
        "A1": " Occipital lobe - motion detection",
        "A2": "Temporal lobe - emotion and fear responses",
        "A3": "Parietal lobe - spatial awareness",
        "A4": "Cerebrum - Memory formation",
        "correct-answer": 1, 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Because the resting potential is _______, depolaration means ________",
        "A1": "negative, more positive",
        "A2": "negative, more negative",
        "A3": "positive, more positive",
        "A4": "positive, more negative",
        "correct-answer": 1
    },   
]